Ayush Vatsyayan

M +91-971-143-3344 vatsyayan.ayush@gmail.com Gurgaon, India

Profile

BigData Professional with 9+ years of R&D experience. Experience in Analytics, including basic statistics and machine learning, and Application programming, including architecture design and software development, in various technologies such as Python, R, Scala, Apache Spark, Apache Hive, HDFS, Java/J2EE.

Experience

Manager, Inductis (India) Pvt Ltd/Exl Services, Gurgaon, India - Jan 2017 - Present

• Technically leading large team for migrating financial data from SAS to HDFS/Hive. Responsibilities include migrating data from SAS to HDFS using Apache Sqoop, cleaning and transforming data in pyspark, and validating the data in SAS.

Technical Specialist, Nokia, Gurgaon, India - June 2014 - Jan 2017

- Charging Analytics: Responsible for architecture design and development of Analytics
 dashboard for telecom operators. Tasks included understanding CDR data, loading
 data in HDFS, exploring data in hive over zeppelin, implementing statistics and machine
 learning use cases in Apache Spark.
- * Swift: Technically leading small team for automating product installation, configuration, and testing over linux system in Python.

Sr Analyst, Accenture, Gurgaon, India - Apr 2013 - June 2014

 Marketing Analytics Platform: Contributed as application developer for Implementing forecasting module interface of marketing mix product in EXTJs and Javascript.

Sr. Engineer, Alcatel-Lucent India Ltd, Gurgaon, India - May 2010 - Mar 2013

- Reporting and Analytics: Contributed in the ETL part of the application including implementing REST interface, implementing admin module in struts2. The application was responsible for proving OLAP dashboard over data by different API components in the application. Also contributed in the Hadoop and Cassandra POC in the later phase.
- SMP: Responsible for design and development of alarm correlation module in Apache
 Drools and Java. The alarm correlation was responsible for correlating multiple SNMP
 traps in order to identify the root cause.

Associate S/W Engineer, Value First Messaging, Gurgaon India - Mar 2008 - Apr 2010

- MIS: Responsible for implementation of reporting solution on the large amount of Pace API data. The solution was implemented over BIRT with Jsp/Servlets, Javascript, and Mysql.
- PACE API: Contributed as application developer for developing API in Java/J2EE and Mysql to provide the SMS capability to any application or enterprise system.

Skills

Programming Languages

Python 2.7/3.x, R programming, Scala, Java/J2EE, Pyspark, HQL (Hive query language), Mysql, HTML, Javascript

Continued...

Programming Frameworks

Apache Spark 2.2, Apache Hive, HDFS, Yarn, Hibernate 3.x, Struts2, Drools 5.x, BIRT, ExtJs, Twitter Bootstrap, Junit 4.5, EasyMock, Mockito, Apache CXF, Jboss, Apache Tomcat, Node.js, GIT

Concepts/Methodologies

OOP/D, Test Driven Development, Agile

Education B.Tech (UPTech University) - 2007

Personal Details DOB: 22/11/1987

Nationality: Indian